Bellman forward algorithm is an algorithm that finds the shortest path on a graph and initial cost value
is assigned to each point.
The starting point is set to zero and all other points are set to infinity.
One of the edges is selected.
So for a convenience, we've selected the A B edge.
The cost of each reversal from one and from endpoint to end point on the selected graph is calculated.
The calculation is performed by taking the cost of the initial point, plus the cost of moving, so
zero plus nine will be calculated and carried it out to be so calculation is carried out in one direction
at a time, while either direction is fine for convenience.
In this explanation, we will first calculate the direction from the point with the smaller cost to
the point with the larger, larger cost.
The current cost of eight point A is lower, so we will conclude that reversal from point A to point
B first, then point A's cost is zero.
The cost of getting from point A to point B is zero plus nine, which is equal to nine.
So if that calculate result is less is lower than their current value, then the cost is updated to
the new value.
So nine is lower than infinity.
Then it will be updated to nine.
When a value is updated, we record the path and which point it came from in the diagram.
The path is displayed in orange.
Moving on, we calculate the opposite direction of getting from point A to point B from point B's cost
is nine.
So the cost of getting from point B to point A is nine plus nine, which is equal to 18.
When we compare it with when we compare this with it with Point A's current value, its current value
is found to be lower.
So the cost is not updated when moving from that point, with higher cost to a point with a lower cost
that edges cost does not get updated as long as its cost is positive.
So the same operations will be performed and all at just the order of the edges is up to us.
But this time, for convenience, we will make calculations starting from the edges on the left side.
So we select see we update its cost, which is equal to two.
Likewise, we select another edge from B and C, we update the cost.
So from C to be, it will be a cost us six.
And from A to C will be two.
So two plus six will give us there were eight.
So we can go from A to B not costing us nine, which is directly.
We can go to C and then from C, we can go to B by costing eight.
So a c b is lower than A to B directly.
Now we see that if going from point A to point B, the cost is actually lower to go through points C,
then go, then to go from point a directly.
The coast updates are performed on all edges, so we can update this, and one round of updates was
made.
Now, the update operation is repeated on all edges until no more coast dates occur, so we try to update
here until no more coast updates occur.
OK, so we go through all the parties until no more updates occur, so no more coast update occurs.
So we stopped the operation at this point.
The algorithm's search finishes and find the shortest path from the starting point to each other point
has been found.
Let's think about why the shortest path gets found by such operation.
The scene has been returned to its initial state.
It's time or this time, let's carry out the update operation for all edges in the opposite order.
In other words, from the edges on their eye, the edges that they're left, so the edges came from
there from the starting point A are updated last.
So we start from G.
We update it and try to make this one round of updates was made.
We can see that after one round of updates, only the costs of the Ford at that point searchable from
the starting point, a in one move have been one move have been update.
Well, or we will start try a second round of updates.
Another round of updates.
Let's see.
So we have found this.
These courses have been finished the second round so we can see that after two rounds of updates, only
the cost of the four that points reachable from starting point two in two moves have been updates.
Actually, after performing the update operation and times, it's guaranteed that the shortest path
will be found for all points and moves or fewer away from a starting point.
The diagram has had two rounds of updates, so just so the shortest path is from the starting point
to all points to moves or fewer away will have been found, at the very least.
So the shortest path is only for the points, two moves or fewer, fewer away.
So even though the path to point f veer a c d f has a lower cost, it requires three moves and so it's
not considered.
Also, although the shortest path to point B has been found to take three moves, this this just has.
I happened to be discovered due to the order in which the edges were updated.
In other words, depending on the order in which the edges are updated, there are times when shorter
spaces are discovered that require more moves than the number of updates around.
So given that the shortest passes and moves or fewer away are found after an update, operations have
been carried out.
How many times?
How many times should we carry out the update rotation given end points?
And given that the same point is not arrived back at, we have assured that we would be able to arrive
at all points in and minus one moves.
In other words, if we carry out and minus one update operations at 30, most at the very most the shortest
path to all points will be found.
So also, if we if a long way along the way, we there were no more updates to be made, we could say
that the shortest path is have all been determined and the operations and there.
Let's assume the update operations for the diagram until the shortest best points have been found.
So now let's assume the update.
That we will need is been found the shortest way have been found.
OK, so we are trying to update, trying to find.
The shortest way, so there is no more a date to be made, so the operation is stopped.
We were able to to derive the shortest path as to all points, just like before a c d e f g.
This is the shortest flight.
Moreover, if that cost differs between the coming and going passes between A and B as any graph, and
even if only one way of travel is possible as in the case of the other, just like in this case.
So the Bilmem four can correctly find the shortest way.
Graphs where the direction of edges is fixed, as in the diagram are called directed graph and we have
learned about them and we have implemented them and C and Java in the previous videos and a graph where
the direction of the edges is not fixed at the are not fixed are called undirected.
The graph also, we have learned about them and we have implemented them in C and Java.
So.
What happens when there are some negative costs as well?
Negative costs would defer defer to the minus three on the C B match in this thing.
It's difficult to imagine what it means for the cost to be a negative value, but as an example, let's
imagine moving in a car from starting point A to point.
We can think of four of each cost as expressing the amount of fuel consumed.
In that situation, if we think of there being a gas station where we can replenish our fuel in the
area with negative cost, it might be easier to understand with the Belmont Ford.
Even in situations like that, this.
That incorporate negative costs, the shortest path is are correctly found.
So this is the shortest.
So it would be appeared at the shortest path would be found without issue.
But the total cost of a round trip between a C and B would be minus one.
Death is like this called negative cycles.
When there is a negative cycle, you can make that cost lower and lower without ending by continuing
in cycles around it.
Thus, there is no way to find the shortest path because there is a negative path when trying to find
the shortest path.
And then the graph with bilmem flawed algorithm.
No matter how many times you carry out updates, some points values will change so it never finishes.
Actually, with Bill Mumford's algorithm update should be completed after a number of points minus one
operation.
So if the number of updates meet or exceeds and times, this means there is a negative cycle somewhere
in the graph.
And this is very important.
As you just so that moment for the algorithm is an algorithm with a large amount of calculations, but
it can find the shortest offers even when there are negative costs.
And it can also detect where when there is a negative cycle.
So this is all for them, and for now, let's try to implement development for adequate vitamin C and
let's solve the exercise and implement the little known for adequate and job.